Ahmad Faisal Ridwan

Web Application Developer, Full Stack Application Developer

Ciputat Timur, Tangerang Selatan 089683349234 ahmadfaisal.ridwan@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

PT. Diksha Teknologi Indonesia, Jakarta — Full Stack Application Developer

Aug 2023 - Present

Developing Web application and API for mobile applications for supporting supply chain business process, integrate application with whatsapp's service for notification, managing project documentation, Fixing bugs and pentest findings.

Freelance, (Remote) — PHP Laravel Developer

Aug 2023 - Aug 2023

Developed Landing page with CMS and registration feature for website Terima Cash In (https://terimacashin.com/).

PT. Mitra Integrasi Informatika, Jakarta — Application Developer

Aug 2020 - Jul 2023

Work placement at PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk - Head Office - Sudirman.

Developing and maintaining the BRIMOLA web applications, BRIMOLA API, DWH Scheduler, DB Migration Scheduler, and Service Dashboard BRIMOLA. I have also contributed to the BRISTORE web-application. Develop systems with security standards provided by Bank Rakyat Indonesia. The system's quality check applied layered checks starting from QA to pentest.

Freelance, (Remote) — PHP (Laravel) Developer

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

Developed an Inventory Management System applications for Citra Baja store and Mitra Jaya Electronics store.

Freelance, (Remote) — PHP (Codeigniter) Developer

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022

Developed a web-based Human Resource Management System (HRMS) application with a team for PT Kasen Indonesia and PT Roki

ABOUT ME

I'm Ahmad Faisal Ridwan.

Experienced Application

Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry.

Skilled in PHP (Codeigniter and Laravel), and Python. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Informatics Engineering from UIN Syarif Hidayatullah Jakarta.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

PHP (Codeigniter and Laravel Framework), Python, Javascript, Golang

DBMS:

MySQL

Other Skills:

JQuery, Vue, RESTful Web Services (API), RabbitMQ Message Broker, Docker, Pandas, Pentest Fundamentals

LANGUAGES

- Indonesia (Fluent)
- English (Intermediate)

Indonesia. In this HRMS project, Worked on the Attendance and Payroll modules.

PT. Lyrid Prima Indonesia, Jakarta — PHP Developer

Apr 2019 - Apr 2020

Developed and maintained web-based applications. Such as Smart Estate Management Systems, Inventory Management Systems, Donation Management System.

PT. Manna Solusindo, Tangerang — Delphi Programmer

Nov 2018 - Apr 2019

Developed and maintained Human Resource Management Systems (Web and Desktop) using Delphi programming language.

EDUCATION

UIN Syarif Hidayatullah, Jakarta— Bachelor Degree

2014 - 2018

Majoring in Informatics Engineering.

CEP-CCIT Fakultas Teknik UI, Depok — Professional Programme

2013 - 2015

Majoring in Information Technology of Sharia Banking.

PROJECTS

Supply Chain Management — PT Diksha Teknologi Indonesia

- Developing WEB application and API for mobile applications for supporting supply chain business process.
- Developing notifications feature integrate with whatsapp's service using php (codeigniter), python, and rabbitmq.
- Managing project documentations.
- Fixing bugs and pentest findings.

Landing Page Terima Cash In — Freelance

- Developed Landing page based on given design.
- Developed CMS and registration feature

ACHIEVEMENTS / AWARDS

- Best Student on Information Technology of Sharia Banking Programme, CEP-CCIT Fakultas Teknik Universitas Indonesia (2015)
- Finalist Project Competition CCIT-EXPO at CCIT Faculty of Engineering, Universitas Indonesia (2015).

BRIMOLA — PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika

- Developing and maintaining BRIMOLA Web application and Mobile API
- Developing and maintaining BRIMOLA database migration scheduler for database replication
- Data warehouse scheduler, transforming data from raw data into a more meaningful form
- Developing and maintaining BRIMOLA consumer for background process reporting
- BRIMOLA dashboard services, provide API service used for BRIMOLA dashboard application
- Integrated BRIMOLA System with third parties API (BRIVA, Direct Debit, LinkAja, BRIAPI, IBBIZ, and Pertamina)

BRISTORE — PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika

- Enhance Bulk Upload products system
- Enhance product management features on the BRISTORE mobile API
- Enhance product management features on the BRISTORE web application
- Add reporting features on the BRISTORE web application

Inventory Management System — Freelance

- Develop Inventory Management System. All features were worked on. This system can be used for multiple companies. The features include company management, user management, item management, purchase activity management, sales activity management, stock management, expense management, and reporting.

HRMS — Freelance

- Develop HRMS System, The work involves attendance, payroll features and reporting. This application had been used in the companies PT Kasen Indonesia and PT Roki Indonesia.

Dashboard Web Based Application— PT Lyrid Prima Indonesia

- Develop dashboard web based application for monitoring compressor
- Analyze system requirements based on interview to the user
- Handling bugs and errors

Donation Management System — PT Lyrid Prima Indonesia

- Analyze system requirements based on interview to the user
- Design database
- Developed web application based on system requirements
- Create API for mobile application
- Handling bugs and errors

Inventory Management System — PT Lyrid Prima Indonesia

The application records data of purchasing activities (Purchase order, receive item, purchase invoice, purchase payment), production activities, and sales activities (Quotation, Sales Order, Sales Invoice, Delivery Order, Receive Payment).

- Analyze system requirements based on interview to the user
- Design database
- Develop web application based on system requirements
- Handling bugs and errors

Smart Estate Management System — PT Lyrid Prima Indonesia

The application used for helping a real estate management office staff to generate monthly billing invoice of the residence, to record real estate income and expenditure.

- Analyze system requirements based on interview to the user
- Design database
- Develop web application based on system requirements
- Handling bugs and errors.
- Integrated with smart gate system

HRMS — PT Manna Solusindo

- Develop web based version of Human Resource Information System from existing desktop based application
- Read functional requirement document and collaborate with system analyst in creating additional features
- This application is used to help the company in recording employee hiring, employee attendance, employee payroll, and reporting system

TRAININGS

Web Penetration Testing Fundamental *Cyber Academy Indonesia (November 2021)*

Database Administration Fundamentals

Microsoft Technology Associate (23 November 2017)

Software Development Fundamentals

Microsoft Technology Associate (19 November 2016)

The 12-week Internship Program

ACCESS English School (February 2013 – April 2013)

English Extension and Culture Camp

ACCESS English School (February 2013)